tadpoles.com 2019-04-13

# Privacy for Tadpoles

**Personal Information**

We consider all information captured using Tadpoles to be a private communication between childcare providers and parents. No personal information is shared with any external parties, and communications are only shared with a parent if a provider has explicitly invited the parent to establish communications. All communications are handled via the parent's email address. In order to create an account on tadpoles.com parents are required to validate their email address and only have visibility to information shared to that specific email address. 

**What do we use your information for?**

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: 

  * To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To send periodic emails, newsletters, and updates. The email address you provide for registration will only be used to send you information and updates pertaining to our services.

**How do we protect your information?**

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. All supplied sensitive information is transmitted between providers and Tadpoles via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and encrypted. 

**Google authentication**

For those users who have Gmail accounts, we require that they authenticate through Google. This is for the following security and privacy reasons: 

  * Authenticating directly to Google prevents the user from ever having to send any password information to our system
  * Authenticating directly to Google allows for the user to use the most secure authentication mechanisms such as two factor authentication
  * Authenticating directly to Google allows us to know absolutely certainly that the user is the owner of the email address provided

In order to ensure that the user authenticating via Google is the actual owner of the email address and therefore allowed to view communications that have been sent to that email address, we ask for access to verify the user's Google profile and email address. This does not grant any access to any user content stored with Google, nor does it grant access to post any information to the user's Google+ account. We do not and will never request access to any emails, photos, Google+ posts or any content in the user's Google+ account. 

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

**Privacy Statement**

The information collected from childcare providers during our registration process is child’s first name, parent's e-mail address, and birth date. We collect birth dates to validate age-appropriate daily activities reports. We may collect other personal information in order to improve communication between providers and parents.

**Consent and Licensee Requirements**

Tadpoles Licensee “Provider” will provide notice to parents or obtain parental consent to send electronic communication via the Tadpoles program. Provider may collect the parent’s contact information to send the parents electronic communication in regards to child’s activities. Provider will make reasonable efforts, taking into account available technology, to ensure that the parent receives notice of the program.

**Parent Refusal**

At any time parents can request that any personal information be deleted or they be removed from the Tadpoles program. A parent can contact the childcare director or schools department supervisor to change or delete the personal information collected about his or her child.

**Parent Emails**

Tadpoles does track the delivery status of daily report emails to allow a childcare provider to ensure a parent has received a critical piece of information. If you would like to opt out of that delivery status update please notify us at talk.to.us@tadpoles.com

**Children’s Privacy**

Tadpoles does not permit children under 14 the ability to access, post publicly or otherwise distribute personal information.

*The term “parent” includes legal guardians. 

**Tadpoles**  
4500 East-West Hwy  
Suite 300  
Bethesda, Maryland 20814  
USA  
1-800-637-3652
